let's try a practice problem regarding
enthalpy of vaporization. so the question
is how much heat is required to vaporize
1.500 liters of water at 37 degrees
Celsius so in order to answer this we
need to know that the density of water
at 37 degrees Celsius is actually just a
hair under one gram per milliliter which
is what we're used to we're going to use
point nine nine three four grams per
milliliter to be very specific and then
the heat of vaporization of water at 37
degrees Celsius is forty three point
four six kilojoules per mole so this is
all the data you need to answer this
question go ahead and give it a try.
let's take our one point five zero zero
liters of water and we're gonna want to
do some stoichiometric calculations so
we've got to get two moles our goal is
always going to be to get two moles
somehow with these things so let's take
our one point five zero zero liters and
we want milliliters because our density
was grams per milliliter so let's
multiply by a thousand milliliters over
one liter and we're gonna get 1,500
milliliters now that we have milliliters
we can use our density 1500 milliliters
times zero point nine nine three four
grams per milliliter and that is going
to give us a mass of fourteen ninety
grams so that is the mass of water
contained in that volume of water
specifically at this temperature 37
degrees Celsius right if we had a
different temperature things might be
slightly different then we take our
fourteen ninety grams of water and we're
gonna multiply by one mol / eighteen
point oh two grams that's the molar mass
of water and we know we therefore have
eighty two point six nine moles of water
that's how many moles of water are in
this volume of water at this temperature
then lastly we can just use the given
thermo chemical data we know that eighty
two point six nine moles times forty
three point four six kilojoules of
energy required per mole for
vaporization to occur that's going to
give us a total of three thousand five
hundred ninety four kilojoules of energy required to vaporize this volume of water at this temperature.